<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poligraf.io</title>
    <link>https://poligraf.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on poligraf.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://poligraf.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot read property ‘graphiteVersion’ of null</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/cannot-read-property-graphiteversion-of-null/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/cannot-read-property-graphiteversion-of-null/</guid>
      <description>After upgrading to 0.99f version, you get this error on any dashboard:
Starting from Grafana 4.5, the version of the graphite datasource is mandatory and that’s why we update a record in the sqlite database during the upgrade process. For a small population of users, this record is not updated for an unknown reason.
To correct that issue, you simply need to force the “0.9” version in the graphite datasource:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are now using version 0_99f &#34;Traptown&#34;!</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99f-traptown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99f-traptown/</guid>
      <description>Today we are proud to announce the release of the sixth PoliGraf update: 0.99f codename “Traptown” Edit 29 may 2019: For the few of you that would encounter this issue after upgrading, please refer to this post for a fix:
In this new version, we’ve added the support of the new vSAN 6.7U1 API (included in the 0.99e1 emergency patch).
  New features
 SuperStats vCenter Bad Events Early Storage Pod (aka Datastore Cluster) support Grafana 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Simple Became Complicated</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/how-simple-became-complicated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/how-simple-became-complicated/</guid>
      <description>Few months ago, we had the amazing opportunity to deploy PoliGraf in a *BIG* company. Think petabytes scale.
In the past, we have already been challenged to make our tool scalable, but not that much:
 50+ vCenter 6000+ ESX 115000+ VM 18000+ datastores 1000+ clusters 200ms+ network latency for half vCenter  After many hours of hard work, almost total rewrite of our code and a massive use of hash tables, we are proud to show you a sneak peek of the next PoliGraf version (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSAN dashboards empty after vSphere 6_7U1 update</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/vsan-dashboards-empty-after-vsphere-6-7u1-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/vsan-dashboards-empty-after-vsphere-6-7u1-update/</guid>
      <description>Due to some unexpected changes in the vSAN 6.7U1 APIs, your PoliGraf appliance won’t be able to fetch vSAN metrics after updating your vCenter in 6.7.0 build 10244857 (aka U1). You’ll also get this error in the log:
 DIE Can’t call method “apiType” on an undefined value at /root/VsanPullStatistics.pl line 136.
 Today we’re releasing a quick fix (0.99e1) on top of the 0.99e version, meaning you CAN’T apply this fix on previous version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are now using version 0_99e &#34;White Forest&#34;!</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99e-white-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99e-white-forest/</guid>
      <description>Today we are proud to announce the release of the fifth PoliGraf update: 0.99e codename “White Forest” In this new version, we’ve added the support of the new vSphere 6.7 &amp;amp; vSAN 6.7 APIs.
  New features
 PoliGraf data Export &amp;amp; Import vmhba traffic in cluster dashboards VM network usage (bandwidth) VM disk usage (bandwidth) vCenter Active Sessions (per user)    Enhancements and fixes
 VSAN Resync dashboard boost (per reason) Network errors and dropped counters Early HTTPS support Wrong mem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Nova Prospekt</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/welcome-to-nova-prospekt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/welcome-to-nova-prospekt/</guid>
      <description>Today we are very proud to announce the release of the fourth PoliGraf update: 0.99d codename “Nova Prospekt” In this new version, we’ve added the support of the new vSphere 6.5 &amp;amp; vSAN 6.6 APIs. We also embed the very up to date Grafana 4.3 and all the Debian 8.8 packages upgrades for security concerns.
  New features
 Multi Cluster Top N VM Snapshot (many thanks to Jo for this great idea) All|Multi Datastore Usage Distribution Multi Cluster vCPU pCPU All|Multi Cluster Top N VM Latency Multi Cluster Top N VMFS Latency SAN Monitor 2nd FTT VSAN Monitor “66” (resyncRead &amp;amp; client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are now using version 0_99c &#34;Citadel&#34;!</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99c-citadel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99c-citadel/</guid>
      <description>Today we are proud to announce the release of the third PoliGraf update: 0.99c codename “Citadel” In this new version, we’ve added the support of the new VSAN 6.2 API but also FreeNAS and Windows!
  New features
 VSAN Space Usage Report FreeNAS SexiPanel Windows SexiPanel VMware VSAN AF Monitor Multi VSAN Monitor    Enhancements and fixes
 VSAN witness support removed (no useful stats) T10 support in VSAN NAA Latency dashboard Handle PerformanceManager spikes Various bug fix OVF properties support    To upgrade your existing appliance go get the SexiGraf Update Package on GitHub and use it in the Package Updater (you won’t lost any data of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Scale Ability</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/big-scale-ability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/big-scale-ability/</guid>
      <description>You may wonder how big you can go with PoliGraf? It turns out you already got the answer in your question: BIG
Check out how many ESXi and VM you can monitor with a single PoliGraf appliance:
Yes, this is 968 ESX, 12405 VMs, 155 TB of RAM and 1.7 PB of storage over 18 vCenters. We only pushed up the appliance to 8 vCPU and 16GB of vRAM to support the load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are now using version 0_99b1 &#34;Xen&#34;!</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99b-xen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99b-xen/</guid>
      <description>Today we are proud to announce the release of the second PoliGraf update: 0.99b1 codename “Xen” Edit 10 feb 2016: For those of you who downloaded the previous version 0.99b, please apply the 0.99b1 patched version. You can check your current version in the Package Updater admin module.    New features
 vSphere Top N VM Stats vSphere Top N VM Overcommit VSAN Resync VSAN NAA Latency VSAN DiskGroup Capacity    Enhancements and fixes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are now using version 0_99a &#34;City 17&#34;!</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99a-city-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/you-are-now-using-version-0-99a-city-17/</guid>
      <description>Today we are proud to announce the release of the first PoliGraf update: 0.99a codename “City 17“   New features
 VSAN Top N vmdk Cluster Multi ESX LiteStats    Enhancements and fixes
 House Cleaner Log Viewer Authentication fix Various bug fix    To upgrade your existing appliance go get the SexiGraf Update Package on GitHub and use it in the Package Updater (you won’t lost any data of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cannot complete login</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/cannot-complete-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/cannot-complete-login/</guid>
      <description>If you suffer from a PEBCAK disease, you might encounter a “Cannot complete login due to an incorrect user name or password” error. In that case, please remove you ski gloves and try again 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The roooooooot situation</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/blog/the-roooooooot-situation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/blog/the-roooooooot-situation/</guid>
      <description>If you got this behavior, it’s because you’re in a RDP or ICA session trying to enter your root credentials. The only way to work around is the famous VMware KB Repeated characters when typing in remote console:
keyboard.typematicMinDelay = &amp;quot;2000000&amp;quot; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any issue regarding PoliGraf, an idea of how we could make it better, or if you just want to tell us how you’re using it, feel free to contact us on Twitter or Github, rest assured we will respond to that (yes, we aren’t bots, yet)!
If you want to come visit us and buy us a 🍺, feel free to meet us here
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>download</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/download/</guid>
      <description>Here you will find all links to resources we used to build PoliGraf. There was a lot of work done to bring it to life, and we wanted to share with you all the awesome Tools/Posts/HowTo’s we used to do it.
Grafana  Grafana Screencasts (YouTube) Grafana: L’interface web de Graphite Building a Dashboard with Grafana, InfluxDB, and PowerCLI  Graphite  Graphite Documentation Installing Graphite and Grafana on RHEL 6, 7, or Ubuntu in under 30 minutes 10 Things I Learned Deploying Graphite vCenter VM monitoring with Graphite Installing collectd and graphite Introduction to Tracking Statistics on Servers collectd Write Graphite plugin SSC Serv Graphite plug-in Using PowerShell To Send Metrics To Graphite Graphite+Megacarbon+Ceres  Everything else  Unnoc vCacti vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>features</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/features/</guid>
      <description>PoliGraf is a vSphere centric Graphite appliance with a Grafana frontend. Here is what’s under the hood:
 Carbon is listening on TCP:2003 so you can send any metrics you like in plaintext (like Windows counters…) vSphere SDK for Perl is used to pull VI and VSAN metrics from VMware vCenter APIs and pushed to carbon. Collectd is here to monitor your PoliGraf appliance (see the Home page) but it will also be used to collect SNMP metrics in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>licensing</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/licensing/</guid>
      <description>PoliGraf is provided under MIT License, as described here:
 MIT License
Copyright (c) 2018 sexibytes
Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the “Software”), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quickstart</title>
      <link>https://poligraf.io/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://poligraf.io/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Here is how you can get and quickly setup this awesome appliance named PoliGraf.
Step 1: Get PoliGraf Download OVA appliance – v0.99f “Traptown”
SHA1 sum is: 4007ede0a95e34b583c997b532294200e8538a7e poligraf.ova  You can find all release notes on our GitHub Milestones page  Default root password is: Sex!Gr@f  Step 2: Deploy PoliGraf appliance aimed to be deployed on a VMware vSphere™ environment which can be achieve via several ways:
 vSphere client vSphere Web Client VMware OVF Tool command-line utility  Step 3: Configure Starting from version 0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>